Karthikeyan Murugesan

karthi1993kn@gmail.com

7867877751

India 9

linkedin.com/in/karthi-keyan- in 062619a5linkedin.com/in/karthi-keyan-062619a5

SUMMARY

Senior .Net Developer with 7+ experiences in the area of analysis, design, Development, testing and implement high-quality software applications. Experience in the client, business tier and data tier application development of complex, n-tiered client-server applications using various technologies. Extensive experience in architecture, design and develop Web Applications with angular and ASP.NET full stack development and domain driver development.

SKILLS

Azure

SPECIALIST - CLOUD SERVICES & SOFTWARE

- Languages (C# plus VB.NET, Javascript, TypeScript)
- .NET Framework
- .NET Core
- ASP.NET MVC, Web API, WCF
- Angular 2+, HTML5, CSS4
- Databases (MySQL, SQL Server, Azure SQL, Graph DB)
- C# unit testing frameworks (nUnit, MSTest, xUnit)
- Entity Framework Core 1.0-2.2
- IoC Containers (Castle Windsor Container, AutoFac)
- Windows forms
- Neo4J

WORK **HISTORY**

Specialist - Cloud Services & Software

Larsen & Toubro Infotech Chennai, Tamilnadu May 2021 - Present

- Attended training programs to deepen professional skillset and assisted in training fellow store associates on existing and new training programs.
- Working as a Backend developer involved in developing WebApi's and Query using Neo4J.
- Worked in API Integration with React Single Page Application.

Technology Analyst

Infosys Limited Chennai, Tamil Nadu Oct 2020 - May 2021

- Designed and developed an application using Angular 2+, HTML5, CSS3, C#, WCF, SQL server 2018 and ASP.Net web API.
- Created the application UI using client-side technologies like Javascript, Typescript, Jquery, Angular, CSS3, HTML5, and Ajax.
- Used Angular-JS and typescript for control validations and data format checking.

Senior Systems Engineer

Infosys Itd Chennai, Tamilnadu Sep 2016 - Nov 2020

- Worked at onshore(Melbourne) for 2 years for a client requirement and handled business peoples directly for requirement discussions and developed a public facing application and a progressive web app (PWA).
- Created the application in .Net framework 4.5 and ,Net Core 3.0 and implement logic using C# and oops concepts.

- Developed form validations on the server side and client side using AngularJS.
- Participated in scrum/agile meetings to update the status of application development.
- Worked in designing and configuration of the Azure environment. Migrated legacy applications to the Azure cloud platform.
- Developed a Windows application using winforms and .Net framework with WCF service components to communicate to third party application for almost 4 years

System Engineer

Infosys Ltd Chennai, Tamilnadu Sep 2014 - Sep 2016

- Supported technology design, testing and execution by providing research-based product and process knowledge.
- Developed, managed, measured and reported on service-level metrics to streamline IT assessment.
- Developing multiple new applications from scratch and supporting multiple existing applications.
- Created a database schema, er diagrams, tables, views, triggers, functions and stored procedures.
- Involved in all the phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including analysis, design, programming, testing, and deployment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering Electronics And Communications Engineering

K.S.Rangasamy College Of Technology Tamilnadu Aug 2010 - Apr 2014